

Massimiliano Bruni

Email: massimiliano.bruni@icloud.com | Mobile: +39 334 924 0665

PROFILE

I am a Software Engineer specialized in Ma- PRIMA ASSICURAZIONI chine Learning. During my career I have real- MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER ized and put into production various projects, Dec 2024 - present | Rome (Full Remote) both proprietaries and Open Source. I love technology and I like working on innovative projects. I work methodically, precisely and with attention to details. I am rational, diligent, hard-working and pragmatic.

LINKS

Github://Maxinho96

LinkedIn://Massimiliano Bruni Medium://Massimiliano Bruni YouTube://Massimiliano Bruni

LANGUAGES

Italian: Native

English: Fluent (B2/C1 level)

SKILLS

HARD SKILLS

Advanced: Python • Machine Learning FastAPI • Flask • AWS • Docker • Kubernetes Airflow • Elasticsearch • Opensearch Kibana • PostgreSQL • Linux • Bash • Git Intermediate: Pandas • Polars • RabbitMQ Huggingface Transformers • Rasa Chatbot Basic: Golang • Java • Keras • TensorFlow Terraform • Cloudformation • Logstash

SOFT SKILLS

Problem solving, for the Engineering studies. Team working, for the projects I worked on. vate tutor and library assistant.

Learning, for my passion to discover the world. Grade: 110/110 cum laude

EXPERIENCE

Technologies: Python

OUTFITTERY

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - MACHINE LEARNING

Dec 2022 - Nov 2024 | Berlin (Full Remote)

I have guided the migration of ML microservices and data pipelines to AWS and completely re-engineered their legyacy architecture for better scalability, reliability and maintainability.

Python • FastAPI • Flask • AWS • Docker • Kubernetes • Airflow • Opensearch • Kibana

PostgreSQL • Pandas • Polars • RabbitMQ • Terraform • Cloudformation

HCL SOFTWARE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - MACHINE LEARNING

May 2021 - Nov 2022 | Rome (Hybrid)

I was responsible of training models, engineering the backend and delivering Clara (a chatbot with custom machine translation) and Al Data Advisor (an anomaly detector).

Python • Pandas • Huggingface Transformers • Rasa • FastAPI • Bash • Docker •

Kubernetes • Elasticsearch • Kibana • Logstash

ASKDATA

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

September 2020 - April 2021 | Rome (Full Remote)

I was responsible of R&D and engineering of Deep Learning models in the NLP field involving Summarization, Machine Translation, Named Entity Recognition and Semantic Similarity.

Python • Pandas • Huggingface Transformers • Flask • FastAPI

EDUCATION

ITALIAN RESEARCH CENTER (CNR)

ADVANCED SCHOOL IN ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE

Practical school with focus on Machine Learning Applications.

October 2019 - April 2020 | Rome

UNIVERSITÀ DEGLI STUDI ROMA TRE

Communication, for the experiences as pri- Bachelor's and Master's Degree in Computer Science Engineering

September 2015 - July 2020 | Rome

CERTIFICATIONS

Year	Released by	Certificate
2024	AWS Certified	Developer Associate
2022	Rasa chatbot	Rasa Developer
		Certification
2021	Coursera	Deep Learning
		Specialization
2020	Italian State	Software
		Engineering License
2015	Cambridge	B2 First
2015	Cisco	CCNA Discovery

HOBBIES

Sports • Technology news • Videogames Board games • Mangas • Hangout

PROJECTS & OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

CLARA (LINK)

A chatbot virtual assistant for Workload Automation.

AI DATA ADVISOR (LINK)

An Anomaly Detection System for Workload Automation.

HUMAN2SQL (LINK)

Translation from spoken language to SQL language.

VIDEO SURVEILLANCE SYSTEM (LINK) OBJECT DETECTION WITH DRONE (LINK)

TELEGRAM BOT: IMAGE CLASSIFIER (LINK)

TRAINING GROUNDS (LINK)

Outfittery's Data Science Framework.

RASA CHATBOT FRAMEWORK (LINK)

HUGGINGFACE TRANSFORMERS (LINK)

YOLOV3 TENSORFLOW IMPLEMENTATION (LINK)